## Dulitha Jayakodige

Newport News, VA ■ +1 757 998 3190 □ dulitha.mj@gmail.com

in www.linkedin.com/in/dulithajayakodige/

Ph.D. Candidate in Physics with 4+ years of research experience in Theoretical Nuclear Physic. Skilled in cleaning, visualizing and model building with large data sets. Data Science enthusiast who looks for an opportunity to exploit Physics, Mathematics, and Programming skills.

## PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Research Assistant 05/2019-present

Thomas Jefferson National Accelerator Facility Newport News, VA.

- Pion Nucleon Scattering using Chiral Perturbation Theory and  $1/N_c$  Expansion
- Data cleaning, analyzing, visualization, and model building using Python and Mathematica

Research Assistant 01/2016 - 04/2019

Graduate Physics Research Center, Hampton University, Hampton, VA.

- Monte Carlo simulations of Quantum Ghost Imaging using Python and Matlab
- Data acquisition using Matlab

Teaching Assistant at Hampton University, Hampton, VA and University of Colombo, Colombo, Sri Lanka

02/2015 - 05/2017

- Teaching and grading Introductory Physics Labs
- Conducting tutorial classes

## **EDUCATION**

Ph.D. in Theoretical Particle Physics

expected December 2023

Hampton University, Hampton, VA

University Of Colombo, Colombo, Sri Lanka

B.Sc. in Physics,

January 2015

Deep Learning Specialization expected December 2022

Deeplearning.AI/Coursera.com

IBM Data Science Specialization March 2022

IBM Skills Network/Coursera.com

## SKILLS AND INTERESTS

**Technical skills**: Advanced in Python, Mathematica, MATLAB, and LATEX; Experienced in SQL, Java, and Linux/Windows operating systems.

Languages: Fluent in Sinhala and English

Awards: 3rd best presentation at the School of Science Research Symposium, Hampton University

Interests: Chess, photography, and hiking

PORTFOLIO https://dulithajayakodige.github.io/